Phoenix, Arizona 85014 | 928.651.1487 | bob.church@gmail.com GitHub: http://bit.ly/BobGit | LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/BobLink | Portfolio: http://bit.ly/BobPort

Robert W. Church

Former QA Manager turned Web Developer with extensive technical industry experience and passion for finding and solving problems. Proven track record in management and highly results-oriented with strong organizational skills.

Skills

Knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, Drupal and Databases (SQL and Mongo) Thorough understanding and practical use of many Microsoft Office Suite programs as well as bug reporting applications such as Jira and project management software including Confluence, Trello and Rally. Experience managing and working in an Agile QA team.

Recent Employment Experience

July 2019 - Current

Republic Services

Scottsdale, AZ

Front-End Developer

- Working as a front-end developer using Angular, involved with upgrading the existing code from AngularJS
 to Angular 7 then moving into Drupal development responsible for updating and maintaining the Drupal
 code for the company's page, as well as updating and creating ptypes to allow content creators to use the
 latest Angular components.
 - Upgrading website components from AngularJS to Angular 7.
 - Writing and fixing unit tests for both AngularJS and Angular 7.
 - Debugging and fixing defects found in TrackJS and Splunk errors from the live site.
 - Updating and maintaining the Drupal based CMS.
 - Part of the on call team for live issues coming from tracking and error reporting systems.

Sept 2015 – August 2018

flaregames GmbH

Karlsruhe, Germany

Product QA Manager

- Ensured timely project delivery with planned capacity, reviewed skill requirements for current and future projects, and developed internal talent to improve in their current roles and progress toward future aspirations while acting as a strong advocate for quality in the product development process.
 - Designed test strategies using a variety of techniques, tools, and technologies including selection of the appropriate methods including cost, efficiency, effectiveness, and balancing available resources.
 - Created productive working relationships with other managers to ensure goal alignment and represent the QA team's contributions.
 - Implemented improvements to optimize and evolve department-wide processes.
 - Interviewed, tested, hired and trained full-time and temporary employees for process continuity, team compatibility, and future growth and development of employees.

QA Test Lead

- Tasked with being the Publishing QA Lead for a project from a third-party developer starting during soft launch through to the project's sunset.
 - Created test plans for feature testing to assist the developer leading up to submissions.
 - Ensured submission testing was complete by the agreed upon release date.
 - Maintained test plans and tested updates to the game throughout the lifecycle.
 - Coordinated with an internal game team and the external developer for project continuity.
 - Managed outsource teams as needed for testing.
 - Deployed test servers using AWS.

Sept 2012 – August 2015

WildTangent Studio

Seattle, WA

QA Test Lead

- Tasked with starting the QA team for the new mobile games studio formed by WildTangent, responsible for testing of all games made internally as well as games created by outsource partners for Android and iOS.
 Also responsible for interviewing and hiring additional QA staff as needed, including hiring contract workers for holiday work load increases.
 - Lead testing on all studio titles, both internally created as well as outsourced.
 - Ensured all titles are tested and released on schedule.
 - Tested updates for existing titles until project sunset.

- Coordinated with producers, developers, and art teams to remain up to date on fast changing requirements.
- Created and maintained in internal beta process to use the larger main office for game feedback before release.

August 2007 – August 2012

PopCap Games

Seattle, WA

Social

QA Test Lead

- Responsible for managing testing on a Facebook connected Bejeweled Blitz iOS project as well as directing and training other testers on the project; work and maintain a live product with regular client and server updates. Responsible for coordinating with other platforms on the project with shared server infrastructure before and during server and client updates.
 - Lead testing on iOS client updates while maintaining the current live product.
 - Coordinated with the customer service department to identifying and resolve user reported issues.
 - Worked with developers and producers to triage and fix bugs and design new features.
 - Trained new testers to assist with client and server push testing.
 - Created and maintained test and training documentation.

Studio

QA Test Lead

- Full-time employee in the studio QA department where with responsibility for ensuring that assigned projects were fully tested and ready for release. Also charged with preparing test plans for assigned projects as well as giving final QA sign off when the project was completed.
 - Lead other testers on multiple projects to ensure the best quality and a timely product release.
 - Maintained open communication with the producers, developers and artists for triaging of bugs and project planning.

Mobile

QA Tester and Lead

- Full-Time employee in the mobile QA department where beginning as a QA tester testing the porting of games into BREW and Java for mobile devices for US specific carriers, then promoted to Lead responsible for ensuring that ports to US BREW devices (including Verizon and Alltel phones) as well as ports to US Java devices for AT&T were thoroughly tested.
 - Responsible for guaranteeing that builds for BREW devices passed the TruBREW certification tests for release.
 - Coordinated with test teams in Dublin, Ireland to complete porting and backfill projects.
 - Maintained robust device inventories.

Education

January 2019 – April 2019

University of Arizona

Continuing Education Certificate Full Stack Web Development

Dact Lm	niawmant	LVNARIANAA
rasi eiii	DIOVILIELL	Experience

Oberon Games, Seattle, WA Software Test Engineer

February – August 2007

Volt, Redmond, WA Software Test Engineer March – June 2006

Mobliss, Seattle, WA Quality Assurance Tester September 2004 – January 2006

Excell, Redmond, WA Software Test Engineer Level II April – September 2004